Scott James

152 Willow Road Dartford, DA1 2QP | Mobile: 07747 089443 | Email: scottaustinjames@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/ | GitHub: https://github.com | Portfolio: https://scottjames.dev/

Profile

I am a creative, self-motivated individual who is passionate about IT, I taught myself how to code while at college and have since gained a career with 5+ years of experience as a full stack developer creating web apps and websites for businesses with a proven increase on their overall online presence, I am now looking for migrating my skills and continue learning and adapting to new software and technologies.

Training and Education

Nescot College Surrey

March 2023 - November 2023

Level 3 Diploma in Software Development

September 2022 - January 2023

TechTalent Academy, Cyber Academy

February 2016 – July 2016

LearndirectMathematics A

English A

North Kent College

September 2013 – July 2015

Pearson BTEC Level 3 Diploma in Professional Competence for IT and

BCS Foundation Certificate Information Security Management Principles

Telecoms Professionals.

Pearson BTEC Level 2 Diploma in Professional Competence for IT and

Telecoms Professionals.

Pearson BTEC Level 2 in ICT Systems and Principles.

Skills

HTML & CSS

React

SQL

WordPress

Apache Server

Customer Relationship Management
(CRM)

Available Server

Active Directory

Windows Server

Windows Server

Work experience

Freelance (Remote), Full Stack Developer

2017 – Present

- Managing client proposals from start to finish, including during the design, print, and production processes.
- Developing a high level of expertise in programming languages such as HTML, PHP, and JavaScript coding.
- Ensuring the site is properly optimized for the search engines (SEO).
- Performing QA testing.
- Write and debug software code.
- Keeping up to date with modern design and developer trends.
- Strong problem-solving skills.
- Strong understanding of web development programming techniques and tools.

PC World (Crayford), Business Advisor

2016 - 2017

- Customer service and in-house customer service training.
- Marketing, presentation, and promotional duties.
- Clerical duties (data entry, record-keeping, appointment scheduling, answering, and routing phone calls).
- Identifying potential business customers for future business development.
- Preparing financial reports and analyzing consumer and competitor behavior.
- business-to-business(B2B) and business-to-customer (B2C) sales.
- Up-selling to customers and businesses.
- Recognize and reach out to clients in businesses.
- Meeting daily, weekly, and monthly KPI.

North Kent College, IT Technician

2013 - 2015

- Recording customer information with a CRM (Customer Relationship Management) system.
- Installing and configuring the network, hardware, and software.
- Repair or replace damaged hardware.

- Troubleshooting network, hardware, and software issues and resolving all IT-related problems.
- Conduct backup activities and disaster preparedness.
- Install and upgrade the computer network.
- Working with Microsoft server and active directory.

Interests & hobbies

Studying towards more IT qualifications, Security+, AWS cloud practitioner, CISMP, Cisco Network+ Game Development I am learning how to create video games in unity while also learning about C# Darts & Golf are perfect sports for me to clear my head and I have met great people after playing in local tournaments.

Personal achievements

Federation of Gay Games 2023, contributing to the organization's digital presence and strategic initiatives. Leveraged technical expertise to enhance website functionality, user experience, and accessibility.

IT Army of Ukraine Cyber Specialist 2022, Wanting to help Ukraine and seeing websites hosted in Ukraine being attacked I joined the IT Army of Ukraine where I was given training material and resources to help fight back against Russian aggression. WebJam1 Winner 2021, Having one week to complete a website based upon the theme of nature, I decided to make a charity website for African elephants and the ivory trade winning me first place for my simplistic creative design.

Arctic Code Vault Contributor 2020, I am one of the lucky few who got their code preserved for future generations in GitHub arctic vault in the arctic mountains of Svalbard.

References

Available upon request